# **ANJALI PAWAR**

## Software Engineer

+91 8369278120

@ anjalipawar2206@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/anjalipawar-4917611a6/

https://github.com/Anjali2206/

☆ https://portfolio-anjalip.netlify.app/

## **SUMMARY**

A skilled Frontend Developer with 2+ years of experience, specializing in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript with expertise in React for building modern, responsive web applications. Experienced in the Banking domain, Committed to delivering exceptional user experiences and staying updated with emerging technologies.

# **SKILLS**

React.Js Jav		ascript (ES6+)	Redux	Thunk	HTML	CSS	Tailwind CSS		Bootstrap	Redux-Toolkit	
Github	Git	Restful API Design		Node.Js	Express.Js	Мо	Mongo DB Jest		React Router DOM		Oracle
SQL Ja	ava	Typescript	Azure								

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Virtusa - Software Engineer

### 05/2022 - Present

#### 1. Client Off-Boarding Application

- · Developed Banking client off-boarding application using React.Js
- This ensures a seamless experience for clients transitioning out of the system, optimizing navigation and scalability.
- · Implemented Atomic design pattern which helped to create more consistent UI with better maintainability.
- · Used Redux-Thunk to manage global state and asynchronous logic within Redux and used ( ES6 ) JavaScript on top of micro-frontend architecture.
- · Used Module federation to build scalable, modular applications by facilitating the seamless integration of independently developed modules introducing dynamic routing.
- · Implemented responsive design and cross-browser compatibility using modern CSS techniques.
- · Performed extensive unit tests using Jest and react-testing-library.
- $\cdot$  Worked in Agile methodologies for incremental development to deliver better application.

#### 08/2021 - 04/2022

## 2. Client On-Boarding Application

- · Maintained on-boarding application which is built on ReactJs, Redux-Thunk, and Hooks.
- This application focuses on creating a responsive and efficient on-boarding experience for clients.
- · Boosted performance by 30% Using advanced features like debouncing and memoization.
- · Implemented shimmer UI to enhance user experience during content loading.
- · Extensively used Json for dynamic component rendering in react.
- · Worked closely with back-end developers to integrate RESTful APIs and implement efficient data fetching strategies.
- · Refactored the code for better efficiency, readability, and performance. Resolved vulnerability issues.

## **EDUCATION**

07/2016 - 10/2020

B.E in Electronics & Telecommunication

MGM College of Engineering and Technology, Kamothe, Navi Mumbai.

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

1. HungerHub (Swiggy Clone): React-Based Food Ordering App

Built highly scalable, responsive app using React, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, Redux, Parcel.

## 2. Netflix Clone: Responsive Movie Watching And Recommendation App

An Innovative Movie App Powered by React, Redux, Tallwind, ESBuild, and OpenAl for Lightning-Fast Loading and Responsive Performance.

# **CERTIFICATION / AWARDS**

Exam AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundaments

React Js [From NamasteReact]

Young Star of the Year Award2023